<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMC Project on VMC</title>
    <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMC Project on VMC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ihrivnac.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build Options</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/examples/build-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/examples/build-options/</guid>
      <description>Overview of the available options for building VMC examples and their default values:
VMC_WITH_Geant4 Build with Geant4 OFF VMC_WITH_Geant3 Build with Geant3 OFF VMC_WITH_Multi Build with multiple engines OFF VMC_INSTALL_EXAMPLES Install examples libraries and programs ON Geant4 VMC build options are automatically exported in Geant4VMCConfig.cmake. If Geant4 VMC was built with VGM, the VGM installation path has to be provided via -DVGM_DIR option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Options</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/build-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/build-options/</guid>
      <description>Geant4 VMC includes the G4Root package and examples, which are independent from Geant4 VMC and can be build and used stand-alone. Use of G4Root, VGM, Geant4 G3toG4, UI and VIS packages in Geant4 VMC library is optional and can be switched on/off during CMake build.
Overview of available options and their default values:
Geant4VMC_BUILD_G4Root Build G4Root ON Geant4VMC_BUILD_MTRoot Build MTRoot ON Geant4VMC_BUILD_Geant4VMC Build Geant4VMC ON Geant4VMC_BUILD_EXAMPLES Build VMC examples ON Geant4VMC_USE_G4Root Build with G4Root ON Geant4VMC_USE_VGM Build with VGM OFF Geant4VMC_USE_GEANT4_UI Build with Geant4 UI drivers ON Geant4VMC_USE_GEANT4_VIS Build with Geant4 Vis drivers ON Geant4VMC_USE_GEANT4_G3TOG4 Build with Geant4 G3toG4 library OFF Geant4VMC_INSTALL_EXAMPLES Install examples ON </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building examples application programs - With 3.00.b01</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/examples/examples-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/examples/examples-old/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geometry Definition &amp; Navigation</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/geometry-definition-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/geometry-definition-navigation/</guid>
      <description>Geometry definition The VMC supports two ways of geometry definition:
via Root geometry package (TGeo) via TVirtualMC interface (historically the first way) The first (newer) way is recommended for new users, the way via VMC is kept for a backward compatibility.
Since the version 2.0, user can choose between Geant4 native navigation and G4Root navigation, if geometry is define via TGeo. The choice of the navigation is done via the option specified with creating TG4RunConfiguration object (see VMC examples for more details):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Geant3 - Older Versions</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant3/geant3-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant3/geant3-old/</guid>
      <description>The following instructions apply to the installation of the versions &amp;lt; 2.0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Geant4 VMC - Older Versions</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/geant4_vmc-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/geant4_vmc-old/</guid>
      <description> &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;OpenGL visualization &amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; It is recommended to build Geant4 X11 OpenGL visualization driver used in the VMC examples. It is handled in Geant4 CMake build via the following CMake option:
-DGEANT4_USE_OPENGL_X11=ON &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt; Geant4 VMC &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing VMC</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/vmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/vmc/</guid>
      <description>VMC requires ROOT.
The vmc core package was separated from the ROOT source into a new stand-alone vmc package in the GitHub vmc-project organization. The motivation for this step was a gain in flexibility and faster workflow for new developments of multiple engine mode. The vmc package in ROOT is deprecated since ROOT version 6.18 (its compilation is optional) and it is going to be removed in the next ROOT version, 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/magnetic-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/magnetic-field/</guid>
      <description>The user magnetic field is in VMC defined via TVirtualMagField interface and then set to VMC using TVirtualMC::SetMagField(TVirtualMagField*) function. The propagation of tracks inside the magnetic field in Geant4 can be performed to a user-defined accuracy. See more details in the Electromagnetic Field section in the Geant4 User Guide for Application Developers. Note that while Geant4 allows magnetic, electric and electromagnetic fields, the VMC is currently limited to magnetic fields only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailing List</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/support/mailing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/support/mailing-list/</guid>
      <description>The mailing list is used to keep you up to date about new developments in VMC packages, releases and bug fixes. This list is also used to discuss use of VMC with other users and with the developers. If you want to report a bug, please, use Bug Reports.
To join the root-vmc@cern.ch mailing list, do the following:
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a CERN account, create a light weight CERN account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications List</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/publications/publications-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/publications/publications-list/</guid>
      <description>Please refer to the paper below when publishing results base on simulations with VMC:
Reference paper
Hřivnáčová I et al: The Virtual MonteCarlo,
ECONF C0303241:THJT006,2003; e-Print: cs.SE/0306005
All publications listed in time reversed order:
New Developments in the VMC Project,
I Hřivnáčová, B Volkel 2020 EPJ Web Conf. Volume 245 02005
doi: 10.1051/epjconf/202024502005
Using multiple engines in the Virtual Monte Carlo package,
B Volkel et al 2020 EPJ Web Conf. Volume 245 02008</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running examples</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/examples/running-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/examples/running-examples/</guid>
      <description>First, make sure that you have included all libraries paths in your shared library path.
For all MCs:
/your_path/root_install/lib /your_path/vmc_install/lib For Geant3 only:
path to Pythia6 library /your_path/geant3_install/lib[64] /your_path/examples_install_g3/lib[64] For Geant4 only:
/your_path/geant4_install/lib[64] /your_path/geant4_vmc_install/lib[64] /your_path/examples_install_g4/lib[64] Running examples from Root session The example can be run by calling the provided macros from Root session:
$ cd geant4_vmc/examples/E01 $ root root[0] .x load_g4.C # load all libraries needed to run with Geant4 root[1] .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMC Concept</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/introduction/vmc-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/introduction/vmc-concept/</guid>
      <description>The Virtual Monte Carlo (VMC) allows to run different simulation Monte Carlo without changing the user code and therefore the input and output format as well as the geometry and detector response definition.
The core of the VMC is the category of classes vmc. It provides a set of interfaces which completely decouple the dependencies between the user code and the concrete Monte Carlo, two of which have the key role:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMC Examples</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/examples/vmc-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/examples/vmc-examples/</guid>
      <description>A set of examples of usage of VMC is included in geant4_vmc.
Though provided within Geant4 VMC, they can be built independently and do not require Geant4 installation in case you want to run them with GEANT3 only.
See more details on the VMC Examples web page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMC Project</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/introduction/vmc-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/introduction/vmc-project/</guid>
      <description>The vmc-project GitGub organization provides the following packages:
vmc -&amp;gt; The core of the VMC provides the interfaces and classes independent from the Monte Carlo transport code.
See more in the VMC Core section.
geant3 -&amp;gt; The updated version of Geant3.21 that includes several bug fixes compared to the standard version in CERNLIB. The directory TGeant3 contains the classes which implement the TVirtualMC interface for Geant3
See more in the Geant3 section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bug Reports</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/support/bug-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/support/bug-reports/</guid>
      <description>We use JIRA to track bugs and to gather feature requests.
Report a bug in VMC packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiment Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/examples/experiment-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/examples/experiment-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>VMC was developed by the ALICE Software Project and, since then it was adopted by other experiment frameworks.
ALICE AliRoot - the ALICE software framework (for LHC Run 1 and 2) O2 - the new ALICE software framework in development (for LHC Run 3 and 4) FAIR FairRoot - A simulation, reconstruction and analysis framework, based on the ROOT system, for FAIR experiments </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Geant4 VMC - Special Installations</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/special-installations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/special-installations/</guid>
      <description> &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Geant4 configuration (version &amp;gt;= 9.5) &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; with manual installation (with GNUmake) &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; If you install Geant4 with the GNUmakefile build system and your own environment setting, you need to have set the following environment variables. This way of installation requires an experience in Geant4 and so it is not recommended for novice users.
G4LIB_BUILD_SHARED set to 1 (required) G4LIB_USE_G3TOG4 set to 1 (required) G4VIS_BUILD_OPENGLX_DRIVER set to 1 (recommended) G4VIS_USE_OPENGLX set to 1 (recommended) If Geant4 is installed in a different path than the path to the source tree, the following additional variables have to be set: G4LIB &amp;hellip; path to Geant4 libraries (optional) G4INCLUDE &amp;hellip; path to Geant4 include files (option) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Required and Optional Packages</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/required-optional-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/required-optional-packages/</guid>
      <description>Geant4 VMC requires ROOT and Geant4 installed, then the VMC core package if using ROOT built without vmc enabled, and optionally, it can be built with VGM. See below tips for configuration and installation of these packages.
The path to required and optional packages installations can be defined in the standard CMake way, via the paths to the CMake configuration file:
Geant4_DIR ... path to Geant4Config.cmake ROOT_DIR ... path to ROOTConfig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMC</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/git-vmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/git-vmc/</guid>
      <description>Development version (the whole repository):
git clone http://github.com/vmc-project/vmc.git To switch to &amp;lsquo;pro&amp;rsquo; tagged version 2.0:
cd vmc git checkout v2-0 To switch to the &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; tagged version 1.1.p1:
cd vmc git checkout v1-1-p1 The list of new developments, bug fixes and the required versions of ROOT and Geant4 for each version can be found in the History file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMC Core</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/vmc-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/vmc-core/</guid>
      <description>The core of the VMC, vmc, provides a set of interfaces which completely decouple the dependencies between the user code and the concrete Monte Carlo:
TVirtualMC: Interface to the concrete Monte Carlo program TVirtualMCApplication: Interface to the user&amp;rsquo;s Monte Carlo application TVirtualMCStack: Interface to the particle stack TVirtualMCDecayer: Interface to the external decayer TVirtualMCSensitiveDetector: Interface to the user&amp;rsquo;s sensitive detector The implementation of the TVirtualMC interface is provided for two Monte Carlo transport codes, GEANT3 and Geant4, with the VMC packages listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geant3</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/git-geant3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/git-geant3/</guid>
      <description>Development version (the whole repository):
git clone http://github.com/vmc-project/geant3.git To switch to the &amp;lsquo;pro&amp;rsquo; tagged version 4.1 (compatible with vmc 2.x, ROOT 6.x):
cd geant3 git checkout v4-1 To switch to the &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; tagged version 3.9.p1 (compatible with vmc 1,x, ROOT 6.x):
cd geant3 git checkout v3-9-p1 To switch to the &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; tagged version 2.7.p2 (compatible with ROOT 5.x):
cd geant3 git checkout v2-7-p2 For older versions see the correspondent tag and the required version of ROOT in the history file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple VMC Engines</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/multiple-vmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/multiple-vmc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The VMC package allows splitting the event simulation among multiple engines. The criteria of how to split the simulation have to be defined by the user and among others the decision which engine to be used could depend on
geometry particle phase space particle type any combination of that &amp;hellip; Running multiple engines is fully supported for
GEANT3_VMC GEANT4_VMC This also allows the user to implement his/her own class deriving from TVirtualMC to be used in a split simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitive Detectors and Volumes</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/sensitive-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/sensitive-volumes/</guid>
      <description>Sensitive Detectors Recently (since ROOT version v6.13.04) a new interface to user sensitive detector, TVirtualMCSensitiveDetector, has been added in the set of VMC interfaces. The support for this new way of definig sensitive detector is available since geant3 2.6 and geant4_vmc 4.0.
The user sensitive detectors object should be associated to the selected volumes in the new dedicated MCApplication function: void TVirtualMCApplication::SetSensitiveDetectors()
using the new TVirtualMC function: void TVirtualMC::SetSensitiveDetector( const TString&amp;amp; volumeName, TVirtualMCSensitiveDetector* userSD); Users can also choose whether scoring should be performed exclusively via sensitive detectors or via both sensitive detectors and MCApplication::Stepping() using the function void VirtualMC::SetExclusiveSDScoring(Bool_t); If exclusive scoring is selected, the MCApplication::Stepping() is not called by MC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geant4 VMC</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/git-geant4_vmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/git-geant4_vmc/</guid>
      <description>Development version (the whole repository):
git clone http://github.com/vmc-project/geant4_vmc.git To switch to the &amp;lsquo;pro&amp;rsquo; tagged version 6.2 (compatible with vmc 2.x, Geant4 11.1.x):
cd geant4_vmc git checkout v6-2 To switch to the &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; tagged version 6.1.p2 (compatible with vmc 2.x, Geant4 11.0.x):
cd geant4_vmc git checkout v6-1-p2 The list of new developments, bug fixes and the required versions of ROOT and Geant4 for each version can be found in the history file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics Lists</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/physics-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/physics-lists/</guid>
      <description>Physics list selection Physics Geant4 VMC does not provide a default physics list. User have to choose the physics list from the physics lists provided in Geant4 (see the Geant4 Physics List Guide or include their own physics list. The choice of the physics list is done via the option specified with creating TG4RunConfiguration object. This option is passed asthe second argument in TG4RunConfiguration constructor (see examples for more details).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacking of Particles</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/stacking-of-particles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/stacking-of-particles/</guid>
      <description>The user VMC stack is used differently in Geant3 VMC and Geant4 VMC. Geant3 VMC pops both primary and secondary particles as they are provided by TVirtualMCStack::PopNextTrack(), while Geant4 VMC pops only primary particles using TVirtualMCStack::PopPrimaryForTracking() from the VMC stack.
Stacking of secondary particles is then handled by Geant4 kernel and the user VMC stack only monitors this stacking. By default, Geant4 VMC saves each secondary particle when it starts its tracking (at the the pre-track phase).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tar Files</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/tar-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/download/tar-files/</guid>
      <description>Pro versions Package Version Tar file Tested with vmc 2.0 vmc-2-0.tar.gz ROOT 6.24/06 and 6.26/10 geant3 4.1 geant3-4-1.tar.gz vmc 2.0, ROOT 6.24/06, 6.26/00 and 6.26/10 geant4_vmc 6.2 geant4_vmc-6-2.tar.gz vmc 2.0, ROOT 6.26/10, Geant4 11.1 (with embedded CLHEP 2.4.6.2), VGM 5.1, Garfield 4.0 In general, the VMC packages can be built with the Root version which they were tested with and higher, and Geant4 VMC with the Geant4 version which it was tested with including the patches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geant3 &#43; VMC Content</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant3&#43;vmc/geant3&#43;vmc-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant3&#43;vmc/geant3&#43;vmc-content/</guid>
      <description>Only the Geant3.21 code itself and the implementation of the TVirtualMC interface, TGeant3, provided in geant3 are maintained by the VMC project.
Geant3.21 The updated version of Geant3.21 that includes several bug fixes compared to the standard version in CERNLIB. In this version all Geant3 gxxxxx routines have been renamed g3xxxxx.
The old Makefile system was replaced with a CMake based system since version 2.0.
See also Geant3.21 User Guide</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Cuts and Regions</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/special-cuts-and-regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/special-cuts-and-regions/</guid>
      <description>The way of applying cuts is different in Geant3 and Geant4. In Geant3, the cuts are defined as a limit in energy, which is applied both as an energy threshold (a secondary particle is not produced if its energy is beyond the threshold) and a tracking cut (a particle is stopped when its energy gets below the cut).
Inn Geant4, there is defined a unique cut in range which is then converted to an energy threshold per particle and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Geant4 Classes</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/user-geant4-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/user-geant4-classes/</guid>
      <description>The default Geant4 VMC behaviour, defined by the Geant4 user mandatory classes and user action classes implemented in Geant4 VMC, can be customized by a user by providing his own class derived from TG4RunConfiguration.
Such customization is recommended for including a user own physics list. User has also the possibility to override detector construction and/or primary generation action classes and use an existing Geant4 geometry/primary generator definition with VMC. In other cases, though the customisation is possible and allowed by the design, it has not been tested and so it is not recommended especially for the novice users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings (Old)</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/publications/meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/publications/meetings/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/visualization/</guid>
      <description>Geant4 visualization and UI drivers can be in Geant4 VMC enabled via dedicated CMake configuration options. See more details in Installing Geant4 VMC.
The G3-like functions for visualization defined in TVirtualMC are overcome with the interactive visualization capabilities of both Root and Geant4 geometry modellers, that&amp;rsquo;s why user is encouraged to use these modeller directly. User can set Geant4 visualization options using Geant4 visualization commands, as it is illustrated in the VMC examples in g4vis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching User Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/switching-user-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/switching-user-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>The VMC interface provides a common denominator for all implemented MC&amp;rsquo;s and cannot cover all commands available in a Geant4 user session through Geant4 user interface (UI). Switching between the Root UI and the Geant4 UI gives a user the possibility of working with the native Geant4 UI. It is also possible to process a foreign command or a foreign macro in both UIs:
From Root to Geant4 UI Switching UI: root [0] ((TGeant4*)gMC)-&amp;gt;StartGeantUI();</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-threaded Processing</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/multi-threaded-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/multi-threaded-processing/</guid>
      <description>Geant4 VMC with Multi-threading Geant4 Since version 3.00, Geant4 VMC supports running Geant4 in multi-threading (MT) mode. The VMC application will run automatically in MT mode when Geant4 VMC is built against Geant4 MT. This default behaviour can be changed via the option specified with creating TG4RunConfiguration passed as the fifth argument in TG4RunConfiguration constructor. (Note that the fourth argument, specialStacking option, cannot be omitted in this case.)
The VMC application which has not been migrated to MT should be run in a sequential mode, either with Geant4 VMC built against Geant4 sequential libraries or with Geant4 VMC built against Geant4 MT libraries with disabled multi-threading mode in TG4RunConfiguration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbosity</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/verbosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/verbosity/</guid>
      <description>For many Geant4 VMC classes (like for Geant4 classes) the user can select a higher verbosity level and activate various printings which can help in understanding or debugging his application.
/mcVerbose/all level Set the same verbose level (level &amp;gt;= 0) to all Geant4 VMC objects. If level = 0 no printing is issued, the higher the level is more printings will be issued. /mcVerbose/geometryManager 2 Activate the debug printing from VGM geometry conversion (when geomRootToGeant4 option is selected) /mcVerbose/regionsManager 1 [2] [3] level=1: print the number of regions added via VMC level=2: print also the list of all volumes, the cuts in energy and calculated cuts in range level=3: print also all evaluated energy values /mcVerbose/composedPhysicsList 2 [3] [4] Set the same verbose level to the registed user physics lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbosity for Developers</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/vebosity-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/vebosity-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>For many Geant4 VMC classes (like for Geant4 classes) the user can select a higher verbosity level and activate various printings which can help in understanding or debugging his application. Here we list the commands useful rather for Geant4 VMC developers, for the commands useful for users see Verbosity.
/mcVerbose/SDConstruction 2 Print the volumes IDs (implemented via G4VSensitiveDetector objects) and the maps between volumes and volume IDs. /mcVerbose/runManager 3 Print the logical volume store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source code documentation</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/source-code-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/geant4_vmc/source-code-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Source code documentation has been generated from the source code by Doxygen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/copyright/</guid>
      <description>Copyright (C) 2019 CERN and copyright holders of VMC Project. This software is distributed under the terms of the GNU General Public License v3 (GPL Version 3), copied verbatim in the file &amp;ldquo;LICENSE&amp;rdquo;.
Copyright holders Institutions:
European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), Geneva, Switzerland Institut de Physique Nucléaire dʼOrsay (IPNO), Université Paris-Sud, CNRS-IN2P3, Orsay, France Ruprecht Karls Universitaet Heidelberg (DE)* </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credits</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/credits/</guid>
      <description>The concept of Virtual MonteCarlo has been developed by the ALICE Software Project . Authors: R.Brun1, F.Carminati*1, I.Hrivnacova2, A.Morsch1*
The integration with TGeo, G4Root: A. Gheata*1*
The multiple VMC engines: B. Volkel*1,3*
1 European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), Geneva, Switzerland 2 Institut de Physique Nucléaire dʼOrsay (IPNO), Université Paris-Sud, CNRS-IN2P3, Orsay, France 3 Ruprecht Karls Universitaet Heidelberg (DE)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
