<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installing and Running Examples :: VMC</title>
    <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/index.html</link>
    <description>The following instructions apply to the installation since the version 3.00. Since this 3.00, VMC examples are installed with CMake.&#xA;The VMC examples libraries require ROOT installation and the VMC core package if using ROOT built without vmc enabled. The VMC examples programs can be built against Geant3 with VMC or Geant4 VMC libraries. Only the examples with the multiple engine mode (at present only E03c) can be built with both Geant3 and Geant4 VMC libraries. The VMC_WITH_Multi CMake option has to be set, too, in this special case.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build Options</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/build-options/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/build-options/index.html</guid>
      <description>Overview of the available options for building VMC examples and their default values:&#xA;VMC_WITH_Geant4 Build with Geant4 OFF VMC_WITH_Geant3 Build with Geant3 OFF VMC_WITH_Multi Build with multiple engines OFF VMC_INSTALL_EXAMPLES Install examples libraries and programs ON Geant4 VMC build options are automatically exported in Geant4VMCConfig.cmake. If Geant4 VMC was built with VGM, the VGM installation path has to be provided via -DVGM_DIR option.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building examples application programs - With 3.00.b01</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/examples-old/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/examples-old/index.html</guid>
      <description>The following instructions apply only to 3.00.b01 (beta) version and are kept for reference purpose only. For the production version (3.0) see Installing and Running Examples page. Since Geant4 VMC 3.0.x, there are also provided examples main programs which can be built with either shared or static libraries of all packages. Building with static libraries can make execution faster, especially when running in multi-threaded mode, than when running with dynamic loading of shared libraries in a &#34;traditional&#34; way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running examples</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/running-examples/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/examples/running-examples/index.html</guid>
      <description>First, make sure that you have included all libraries paths in your shared library path.&#xA;For all MCs:&#xA;/your_path/root_install/lib /your_path/vmc_install/lib For Geant3 only:&#xA;path to Pythia6 library /your_path/geant3_install/lib[64] /your_path/examples_install_g3/lib[64] For Geant4 only:&#xA;/your_path/geant4_install/lib[64] /your_path/geant4_vmc_install/lib[64] /your_path/examples_install_g4/lib[64] Running examples from Root session The example can be run by calling the provided macros from Root session:&#xA;$ cd geant4_vmc/examples/E01 $ root root[0] .x load_g4.C # load all libraries needed to run with Geant4 root[1] .x run_g4.C # run with Geant4 or root[0] .x load_g3.C # load all libraries needed to run with Geant3 root[1] .x run_g3.C # run with Geant3 Running examples application programs The example can be also run by calling the executable from the examples installation directory:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>