<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installing Geant4 VMC :: VMC</title>
    <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/index.html</link>
    <description>Geant4 VMC requires the VMC core package, ROOT and Geant4 installed, and optionally, it can be built with VGM. See below tips for configuration and installation of these packages.&#xA;The vmc core package was separated from the ROOT source into a new stand-alone vmc package in the GitHub vmc-project organization. The motivation for this step was a gain in flexibility and faster workflow for new developments of multiple engine mode. The vmc package in ROOT is deprecated since ROOT version 6.18 (its compilation is optional) and it is going to be removed in the next ROOT version, 6.26. The VMC stand-alone is supported since Geant4 VMC 5.0.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build Options</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/build-options/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/build-options/index.html</guid>
      <description>Geant4 VMC includes the G4Root package and examples, which are independent from Geant4 VMC and can be build and used stand-alone. Use of G4Root, VGM, Geant4 G3toG4, UI and VIS packages in Geant4 VMC library is optional and can be switched on/off during CMake build.&#xA;Overview of available options and their default values:&#xA;Geant4VMC_BUILD_G4Root Build G4Root ON Geant4VMC_BUILD_MTRoot Build MTRoot ON Geant4VMC_BUILD_Geant4VMC Build Geant4VMC ON Geant4VMC_BUILD_EXAMPLES Build VMC examples ON Geant4VMC_USE_G4Root Build with G4Root ON Geant4VMC_USE_VGM Build with VGM OFF Geant4VMC_USE_GEANT4_UI Build with Geant4 UI drivers ON Geant4VMC_USE_GEANT4_VIS Build with Geant4 Vis drivers ON Geant4VMC_USE_GEANT4_G3TOG4 Build with Geant4 G3toG4 library OFF Geant4VMC_INSTALL_EXAMPLES Install examples ON</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Geant4 VMC - Older Versions</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/geant4_vmc-old/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/geant4_vmc-old/index.html</guid>
      <description>The following instructions apply to the installation of versions &lt; 3.0. For the required configurations of Root and Geant4 for these older versions see Special installations page. Getting source First get the Geant4 VMC source from the Download page. Root configuration Since the version 2.9 there are no special configuration options for Root needed. The path to Root installation can be defined in two complementary ways:&#xA;a) With the environment variable ROOTSYS: ROOTSYS ... path to Root b) With the Root configuration script root-config ... Root configuration script Note that if the ROOTSYS environment variable is defined the root-config script is not used. For the older geant4_vmc versions (2.x - 2.8) see below. Geant4 configuration (with CMake) To install Geant4 - download the source from Geant4 Download page and follow the Geant4 Installation Guide together with the tips relevant to using it with VMC described below. Geant4 installation options: G3toG4 tool The G3toG4 package is used in geant4_vmc to support geometry definition via VMC with Geant4 native navigation (geomVMCtoGeant4 option). It is required by default. As the G3toG4 package is optional its build has to be activated when building Geant4 by the following CMake options: -DGEANT4_USE_G3TOG4=ON Since the version 2.14, the user applications which build geometry via Root (or Geant4), can be built with Geant4 installed without G3toG4 package. The G3toG4 dependent code in geant4_vmc has to be then inactivated by setting the following environment variable: NO_G3TOG4 ... set to 1 to disable the code dependent on G3toG4 If this variable is set the geomVMCtoGeant4 option is unavailable. &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;OpenGL visualization &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br&gt; It is recommended to build Geant4 X11 OpenGL visualization driver used in the VMC examples. It is handled in Geant4 CMake build via the following CMake option:&#xA;-DGEANT4_USE_OPENGL_X11=ON</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Geant4 VMC - Special Installations</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/special-installations/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/special-installations/index.html</guid>
      <description>Root Configuration for geant4_vmc versions (2.x - 2.8) The older geant4_vmc versions (2.x - 2.8) require Root to be configured with g4root package; for this you have to specify the following configure options:&#xA;--enable-g4root \ --with-g4-incdir=$G4INSTALL/include \ --with-g4-libdir=$G4INSTALL/lib/Linux-g++ \ --with-clhep-incdir=$CLHEP_BASE_DIR/include \ &lt;li&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Geant4 configuration (version &gt;= 9.5) &lt;br&gt; with manual installation (with GNUmake) &lt;/h3&gt; If you install Geant4 with the GNUmakefile build system and your own environment setting, you need to have set the following environment variables. This way of installation requires an experience in Geant4 and so it is not recommended for novice users.&#xA;G4LIB_BUILD_SHARED set to 1 (required) G4LIB_USE_G3TOG4 set to 1 (required) G4VIS_BUILD_OPENGLX_DRIVER set to 1 (recommended) G4VIS_USE_OPENGLX set to 1 (recommended)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Required and Optional Packages</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/required-optional-packages/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/installation/geant4_vmc/required-optional-packages/index.html</guid>
      <description>Geant4 VMC requires ROOT and Geant4 installed, then the VMC core package if using ROOT built without vmc enabled, and optionally, it can be built with VGM. See below tips for configuration and installation of these packages.&#xA;The path to required and optional packages installations can be defined in the standard CMake way, via the paths to the CMake configuration file:&#xA;Geant4_DIR ... path to Geant4Config.cmake ROOT_DIR ... path to ROOTConfig.cmake VMC_DIR ... path to VMCConfig.cmake VGM_DIR ... path to VGMConfig.cmake CMake will also find the CMake configuration files (for ROOT and Geant4) if you source the relevant script from the packages installations (CMAKE_INSTALL_PREFIX) so that they are available in the sestem paths:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>