<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMC Core on VMC</title>
    <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMC Core on VMC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMC Core</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/vmc-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/vmc-core/</guid>
      <description>The core of the VMC, vmc, provides a set of interfaces which completely decouple the dependencies between the user code and the concrete Monte Carlo:
TVirtualMC: Interface to the concrete Monte Carlo program TVirtualMCApplication: Interface to the user&amp;rsquo;s Monte Carlo application TVirtualMCStack: Interface to the particle stack TVirtualMCDecayer: Interface to the external decayer TVirtualMCSensitiveDetector: Interface to the user&amp;rsquo;s sensitive detector The implementation of the TVirtualMC interface is provided for two Monte Carlo transport codes, GEANT3 and Geant4, with the VMC packages listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple VMC Engines</title>
      <link>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/multiple-vmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihrivnac.github.io/user-guide/vmc/multiple-vmc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The VMC package allows splitting the event simulation among multiple engines. The criteria of how to split the simulation have to be defined by the user and among others the decision which engine to be used could depend on
geometry particle phase space particle type any combination of that &amp;hellip; Running multiple engines is fully supported for
GEANT3_VMC GEANT4_VMC This also allows the user to implement his/her own class deriving from TVirtualMC to be used in a split simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
