<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMC Core :: VMC</title>
    <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/user-guide/vmc/index.html</link>
    <description>This chapter presents the core VMC package and the new multiple engine functionality.&#xA;VMC Core Multiple VMC Engines</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vmc-project.github.io/user-guide/vmc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMC Core</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/user-guide/vmc/vmc-core/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/user-guide/vmc/vmc-core/index.html</guid>
      <description>The core of the VMC, vmc, provides a set of interfaces which completely decouple the dependencies between the user code and the concrete Monte Carlo:&#xA;TVirtualMC: Interface to the concrete Monte Carlo program TVirtualMCApplication: Interface to the user’s Monte Carlo application TVirtualMCStack: Interface to the particle stack TVirtualMCDecayer: Interface to the external decayer TVirtualMCSensitiveDetector: Interface to the user’s sensitive detector The implementation of the TVirtualMC interface is provided for two Monte Carlo transport codes, GEANT3 and Geant4, with the VMC packages listed below. The implementation for the third Monte Carlo transport code, FLUKA, has been discontinued by the FLUKA team in 2010.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple VMC Engines</title>
      <link>https://vmc-project.github.io/user-guide/vmc/multiple-vmc/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmc-project.github.io/user-guide/vmc/multiple-vmc/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction The VMC package allows splitting the event simulation among multiple engines. The criteria of how to split the simulation have to be defined by the user and among others the decision which engine to be used could depend on&#xA;geometry particle phase space particle type any combination of that … Running multiple engines is fully supported for&#xA;GEANT3_VMC GEANT4_VMC This also allows the user to implement his/her own class deriving from TVirtualMC to be used in a split simulation. The communication between the engines is handled by a singleton object of type TMCManager such that the user does not have to deal with special implementation details. Hence, pausing an engine, re-starting it or transferring tracks between them is done automatically and at the same time the user stack is kept up-to-date. Furthermore, the same user application derived from TVirtualMCApplication together with the same user stack derived from TVirtualMCStack can be used for both a single engine run or a simulation split among multiple ones.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>